<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tech - Category - Faizaan Khan</title>
        <link>https://faizaankhan.com/categories/tech/</link>
        <description>Tech - Category - Faizaan Khan</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>faizaan[dot]khan3@gmail[dot]com (Faizaan)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>faizaan[dot]khan3@gmail[dot]com (Faizaan)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:32:23 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faizaankhan.com/categories/tech/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Getting familiar with Elasticsearch</title>
    <link>https://faizaankhan.com/tech-elasticsearch-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:32:23 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://faizaankhan.com/tech-elasticsearch-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro Search has become such an extended part of our daily life. Before starting to write this post, I just searched for my fav indie artist Prateek Kuhad on Spotify, plugged in my headphones and here I am making keystrokes with the flow of Dil Beparwah 🙂. With a happy mood what I would like to convey is if you are building a web app, you gotta have the search features.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Web Scraping</title>
    <link>https://faizaankhan.com/guest-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 15:32:23 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://faizaankhan.com/guest-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Did you know that web scraping is integral to the data analysis process? It is because it allows quick and efficient extraction of data from different sources, which can then be processed to glean insights as required. Data Analysis is a huge market today, for some of the software giants it&rsquo;s the source of every decision making, even for small businesses, they get to keep track of the brand value and reputation of their company.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Configuring DynamoDB and basic operations for ruby apps</title>
    <link>https://faizaankhan.com/tech-dynamo-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 15:32:23 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://faizaankhan.com/tech-dynamo-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro Hi, in this blog post I&rsquo;m discussing some of the basic API functions which come in handy to use dynamoDB. These are all well documented on Amazon documentation as well as the library which might use to integrate with AWS, So why this post ? The reason for that is there&rsquo;s a lot of options, and to help you with what you need in the beginning here I list my opinions and my suggested way of doing it.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Bare minimum approach on learning AWS DynamoDB</title>
    <link>https://faizaankhan.com/tech-dynamo-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 15:32:23 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://faizaankhan.com/tech-dynamo-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Why this post ? I am working with DynamoDB for some time now and on that journey I have explored about things that I would like to share. I am no master at Dynamo and nor does one needs to be for being able to utilize it&rsquo;s capacity. Here are most of the bare minimum things you need to know before jumping into starting to integrate DynamoDB to your application or before you chose it as a viable option.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
